ERIC SMITH

Ux Designer - Ui Developer

eric@erchsm.me +1 508 733 4510 Oakland, CA ericsmithux.com github.com/erchsm linkedin.com/in/erchsm

Hello, I'm Eric. I love being creative, exploring, broadening my horizons and crafting delightful user experiences in my projects. When im not coding or designing, I'm a photography enthusiast and love being outdoors.

EDUCATION

March 2015 - May 2015. San Francisco, CA

General Assembly - UXDi

UX Design Immersive Program

Sept. 2010 - May 2014. Amherst, MA

Computer Science - BS

University of Massachusetts Amherst

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3

LESS, SASS, Bootstrap

Sketch 3

Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator

Proto.io, Clickable Prototypes

User Testing, User Interviews

JavaScript, jQuery

Git, Github

NodeJS, AngularJS

EXPERIENCE

Sept 2015 - Present. San Francisco, CA

Wrap Media - UI/UX Designer & Engineer

Created interactive mobile web experiences "aka. Wraps" on the Wrap platform utilizing Sketch and Adobe CC. Worked as a Front-End Engineer on the visual design side of our website. Brought on as designer number 2 and fostered growth of design culture within the startup.

March 2015 - May 2015. San Francisco, CA

Perforce - UX Designer & Researcher

Applied Lean UX principles within a centralized design team via 1-week design sprints. Received & delivered rapid feedback through regular critique sessions. Utilized tools including Sketch, Adobe CC & Proto.io. Conducted generative research to gain insights on our product suite.

March 2015 - May 2015. San Francisco, CA

General Assembly – UXD Program

Covered best practices for User Experience Design during a 10-week immersive program. Created 5 projects in design teams by applying user-centered design principles.

Sept. 2014 - May 2015. San Jose, CA

Cisco - UI/UX Engineer

Member of a small team focused on creating a web application that utilized HTML, CSS and Javascript to allow our users to visualize their WAN or Wide Area Network.

May 2014 - Sept. 2014. San Jose, CA

Cisco – Java Engineer

Member of mid-sized agile team working on the creation of WAN Orchestration Web API's. Worked with JAX-RS to create REST-ful services. Also contributed to the product's developer site.

January 2012 – May 2014. Amherst, MA

People's Market - Co-Manager/Owner

Handled all aspects of running the business including, but not limited to, organizing shifts, facilitating meetings, addressing conflicts, running workshops and handling deposits.

Summer 2011, Summer 2012. Westborough, MA

MLSC Internship - Reflectance Medical

Intern at a "Start-Up" Medical Device Company working in the field of Mobile Device Health Monitoring. Conducted research in the lab, created scripts in Matlab and assisted in the company's first FDA submission.